你也信这个？
Do you believe in God?
我喜欢这里清静 坐在这里觉得很舒服
No, but I enjoy the tranquility here
不检查一下枪？
Want to check the gun?
我相信你
I trust you
不要动
Don't move
我看不清楚
I can't see
你的眼角膜受到损害
Your corneas have been badly damaged
那什么时候好呢？
Will I recover?
视力会受到一定的影响
There is hope, but your sight
会有希望医得好的
will never be perfect
我真的看不见
My sight is so blurred
眼角膜可以换的 放心吧！
We can do an operation, a transplant
我会不会瞎呀？
Will I be blind?
JENNIE 我是警探
Jennie, I'm Sergeant Chang
你记不记得凶手的相貌？
Do you remember the murderer's face?
不要问了 我好害怕
Please leave me alone, I'm so afraid
不要怕
Calm down
救命呀 救命呀！
Help! Help!
救命…
Please help!
起来！
Bastards!
你不要碰我
Just go away,
那两个人让我打跑啦 不要怕
They have gone already, don't be afraid
我送你回家
I'll take you home
JENNIE！
Jennie!
你怎么知道我的名字？
How do you know my name?
每天我都来听你唱歌
I listen to you singing every night
你是谁呀？
Who are you?
听多了好像早就认识
I feel as if I know you
我知道你的眼睛受过伤害
I know you can't see too well
我很想帮你
I've wanted to help,
但一直都没有机会
but I didn't have the chance
在这个世界上
In this world
并不是每一个人都是坏人
not everybody is untrustworthy
让我帮你一次好吗？
Will you let me help you this time?
我看你没事 我会走的
Is it alright for me to leave?
镇定 我帮你看看
Keep calm, let me check it out
原来是只猫！
It's only a cat
那只猫常常跑进来抓烂我的衣服
It often sneaks in and scratches my furniture
它好讨厌的！
Such a nuisance!
你干吗关灯呀？
Why did you turn off the light?
你看得见？
You can see?
只看见影子
I only see shadows
上个月还好一点
Last month it was better
至少还看见一点点轮廓
I could see images
还是开灯比较好 感觉有安全感
Turn on the light it makes me feel safer
你在那里？
What are you doing now?
我在看看围巾
I'm looking at this scarf
还有血迹是不是？
It's got my blood
洗不掉的了这条围巾
stains on it
是那个打伤我眼睛的人留下来的
The man who shot me wrapped it round my eyes
我这一生也不会忘记
I will never forget
我去泡杯茶给你喝
Would you like some tea?
不用了！
No thanks
要的 谢谢你帮了我的忙
It won't take a minute. Sit down please
你先听一首音乐吧！
I'll put some music on
小李 有时候做人太认真
Hey relax, you look exactly like
太古板是不行的
what you are an undercover agent
人家一看你的样子 就知道你是警察
Lighten up or it'll be an open secret
笑一笑
Come on
笑给我看看
Smile!
糟了 那更像个警司！
Now you look like something out of a nut house
曾爷 这家伙是条疯狗 要小心点！
Chang, this guy Eddy's a lunatic. Be careful
他疯 你别跟他一起疯啊
Same to you pal,
小命要紧呀！
watch your ass!
雄哥 让你等 不好意思啊！
Eddy, sorry to keep you waiting
他是谁！
Who the hell's that?
是我的好兄弟 快跟雄哥打个招呼
He's a good buddy. Say hello to Eddy
雄哥！
Eddy
搜搜他！
Search him!
雄哥 干吗那么紧张呀？
Eddy, what's with the security?
我们又不是第一次交易！
It's not our first deal
我好像在那儿见过他？
Maybe I've seen him before
这里二十万 验完货之后再交给你
$200,000 We'll check the guns first
你们在这里做什么？
What are you guys doing?
没什么 长官 我们在这里聊天！
Nothing special, officer. A reunion
打开行李箱给我看看
Open the trunk
快打开行李箱！快！
Open it!
打开呀！
Now!
他妈的 是不是你出卖我？
Damn you! You set me up, didn't you?
你是不是卧底？
Are you a cop?
说！
Talk!
我不是卧底 我永远都不会做卧底
I'm no cop! I didn't betray you
如果你不是卧底 警察怎么会来？
If you ain't, how come he's here?
误会 误会呀！我用性命担保
He's not! I stake my life on it Eddy!
他不是卧底
He's not a cop!
你他妈的也不是好东西！
Lying bastard, I shouldn't have trusted you!
我在警察局见过他的！      误会呀！
- The guy's a cop, I recognise him! - You've got it wrong
曾爷 挺住呀！
Chang, I'll get him
妈的 疯狗！
That shithead!
搞什么的？
Shit
别过来！
Keep back
别动！
Don't move!
你妈的！
Goddamn! Ass Assho
你说完最后一个字
Finish your sentence
我…我…
Assassh
李警官 疑犯黄雄当时协持人质
Inspector Li, the suspect Eddy Wong held a hostage
电车里挤满了乘客
in a crowded tram
你根本看不清楚疑犯在那一个方向？
Could you see him clearly?
是不是！
Could you?
是！
Yes
你凭什么开枪？
Why did you shoot?
感觉！
By instinct
那你有没有考虑过乘客的安全？
Did you consider the safety of the passengers?
开枪之前你有没有发出警告？
Did you sound any warning before you shot?
时间来不及！
There was no time for that
那个女人质本身是有心脏病的
The hostage had a coronary thrombosis
她的家人投诉你未发出警告就开抢
She died of a heart attack
引致使人质受惊而死
Her family have made an official complaint
他的家属要追究你的刑责
You're responsible for her death
荒谬 我怎么知道她有心脏病？
That's crazy, how could I know she had a heart condition?
我调查了黄雄七个多月
I've been on Eddy Hung's case for seven months
我知道这个人有严重的精神分裂
The guy was a maniac
他是有杀人倾向的
He'd shoot anybody for any reason
难道等他把人质杀了 我才开枪？
Should I have waited till he killed her?
被黄雄杀死的那个警察 就活该白死吗？
You forget I'd just seen him kill a cop
他的家人向谁投诉呀？
Who's responsible for that cop's death?
好！你们想怎么写就怎么写吧
Fine! Do whatever you want
反正无论我办那一件案子 都会有人投诉的
I'm used to all sorts of complaints
大不了再记我一过
One more doesn't make any difference
接着！
Catch it!
手还没有练好？
How is the action hand?
没希望了
Pretty useless
一定会练好的
Better use it more
没用了
It won't help
一个枪手 手废了就等于全废了
A one handed killer's out of the action
就算练好了也不如你
I've had my day
他叫汪东源
His name is Tong Weng
跟中南美洲的大毒枭有来往
He works with a drug ring in Central America
为什么要杀他？
Who wants him dead?
别问这么多 做完就算了
No questions. Take it or leave it?
我要一百五十万
1.5 million
太多了吧？
Seems high
干完这一次 你再也找不到我了
This is my last hatchet job
好 反正有人要他死
Alright it's a deal
应该没有问题
Money's no object
这些枪全都没纪录 很干净
These guns are clean. No serial numbers
警方查不到线索
Untraceable
子弹也改装过了 都是你喜欢用的
Explosive head bullets, your favourite
拿起容易 放下难
It's easy to pick it up, hard to put it down
要改变主意吗？
Want to change your mind?
为什么要干？
Why take this job?
JENNIE的眼角膜 已经完全不透明
This one's for Jennie
如果短期内不接受角膜移植手术
If you doesn't have a cornea transplant soon
眼睛可能完全失明
She might lose her sight forever
香港有一个眼库
There is a cornea bank in Hong Kong
可惜一块角膜都没有
But it's always empty
就算有人肯捐出来
When a donation does come in
可是已经有几百人在排队
Someone else gets it first
去外国试试吧
So we're going to try abroad
我有点事要离开几天
I have to leave you for a few days
回来会带你去美国治眼睛
On my return, I'll take you overseas for surgery
你一定要回来
You will come back
一定！
I promise
谢谢！
Thanks!
今天赛龙船
Today is the Dragon Boat Festival
会有很多官方和非官方的重要人物出席
Many VIPs and government officials
议员乡绅参加点睛仪式
will attend the opening ceremony
你们接到的资料
You are assigned to protect them
就是你们要保护的人物
Their information is in your files
大家要格外小心
Make sure you do a professional job
是 长官！
Yes sir!
这种混蛋 还要我们保护
Tony Weng, protecting that scum
请大家注意点睛仪式就快开始了
Attention please! Will all competitors please
请所有参赛的龙船集合到主席台前
assemble before the floating platform for the dotting the dragon's eye ceremony
今天我们很荣幸
It is our pleasure to welcome the president of
请到东源集团总裁汪东源先生
Tung Yuan Financial Corp, Mr Weng
官守议员周思平先生
the Legco councilman, Mr. Si-Ming Chow;
扶轮社香港分社社长朱国华先生
The chairman of Rotary Club, Mr Peter Chu
妇女联谊会会长林李宝珠女士
president of the Professional Women's Association, Ms. Mung-Chu Lee Lam;
还有好多好多位嘉宾
and many other VIPs,
其中有好多还是大家的偶像明星
many of whom are movie stars and pop idols.
在点睛仪式完结之后
After the ceremony,
就会马上举行紧张刺激的最后决赛
the final match of the dragon boat race will begin.
希望各位不要走 尽力争取冠军
We hope all athletes will try their best!
祝大家好运！
Good luck!
汪老板 好 汪老板！
Mr Weng
好…加油呀…
Faster
一定要赢啊！
Good luck
汪老板 请！
Mr Weng, please
盖上他 别惊动群众
Cover him up, keep everything under control
各单位注意…
Red alert, red alert!
紧急情况 主席台发生命案 汪东源被杀
Tony Weng's been shot on the floating platform
子弹是从海上射来的
The shot came from around the fishing junks
凶手就在附近
The murderer must still be nearby
各单位立即展开大搜索截查可疑人物
All units prepare to seal off the area
汪先生只是昏倒
Mr Weng fainted.
没事的…没事啦…
Everything's alright
你们各位继续吧…
Please enjoy your day
曾爷快点 不要被他走甩
Chang!
曾爷 那边爆炸 可能有事发生
Chang, look over there! An explosion
是！过去看看！
Right, let's check it out!
曾爷 别放过疑凶！
Chang, we can't lose him now!
站住！
Freeze!
不要怕
Don't be afraid
不要紧的！
You'll be alright
不要哭！
Don't cry
他在下面 快追 快！
He's down there Step on it!
是！
Ok!
在这儿附近有什么医院？
Any hospital's nearby?
你以为他会去吗？
Think he's got a conscience?
他总不会把小女孩扔下山吧
He won't let the little girl die
小姐 急症室在那里？
Nurse, where's casualty?
来 来 这边！
This way
这孩子怎样啦？
What happened?
她中了枪 快抢救她
She got shot
好！好！好！让我们来
Quickly! Put her down
给她量血压
Nurse, check her blood pressure
准备动手术
Prepare her for surgery
尽快救醒她 准备心电图
Oxygen mask
情况怎么样？
How is she?
脉搏和血压正不正常？
Blood pressure unstable
脉搏微弱
Weak pulse
血压偏低
Blood pressure low
看见一个男人抱着个小女孩吗？
Have you seen a man carrying a wounded child?
进了急症室！
He went to casualty
检查所有可疑的人
Detain anyone suspicious
是！
Yes sir!
先生 你是伤者什么人呀？
Are you related to the patient?
她怎样受伤的？
How was she wounded?
先生！你不要走呀！
Sir, you can't leave now
你叫什么名字？我们要登记的
I have to register your name
那个人呢？
Where is he?
我是警探 继续你们的工作
I'm an Inspector, just carry on
好 好 我们继续
Right, nurses, ignore them
是的…
Yes
不要理他们 救人要紧
Don't mind them, save the girl
是！
Yes
不要骚扰医生
Don't disturb the doctor
把枪放下！
Put your guns down
怎么回事呀？
What happened?
有人朝天开枪
There was a gunshot
在那里？      在那里！
- Where? - Over there!
掩护他们疏散      YES SIR！
- Get everybody out - Yes sir!
我去打电话
I'll call HQ
有什么进展没有？
Any progress on Weng's case?
没有！没有进展
No, none at all
社警官 我跟疑凶碰过面了
I nearly got the suspect
不过让他跑啦
But he escaped
你的感觉不是一向很灵敏的吗？
I thought you had razor sharp intuition?
很多人想看我的笑话
I'm being made to look a fool
这件案子我是要赢 不是要输
so this case is real important to me
赢了 大家都有好处
I don't need you letting me down
你一辈子难得碰到这样的机会
You always were a pain in the ass
唱出好戏给我看看
Do me a favour and prove me wrong
长官 我不会唱戏的
Sir, I do nothing for nobody
我会努力捉拿凶手
I'll get the murderer
不会让你丢脸的
I won't let you lose face
只希望你升官的时候 不要忘了我们！
I hope you don't forget who helped you reach the top
麻烦你 我说你画
I want you to draw the suspect
试试画他的样子
Try, To bring him to life
三十多岁
He's over 30
眼角有些皱纹
He looks determined
很有男人气概
without being ruthless
他跟一般职业杀手不同
Something heroic in his manner
他很冷静 而且机智
Doesn't look like a killer in any way
他的眼睛很有神
Comes across so calm
很有同情心
Acts like he has a dream
很有感情
Eyes full of passion
喂！
Hello
我是小庄
It's me, Jeff
小庄？
Jeff?
怎么你还没有离开这里？
Why haven't you left town?
我要马上拿钱
I want my money now
今晚就要
I want it tonight
今晚！
Tonight!
好 我今天晚上送来给你
Sure, I'll bring it over tonight
汪先生！
Mr Weng!
今天小庄的这件事应该由我负责
You should let me handle Jeff,
你不应该派人去杀他
he's my side of things
他把我抖出来怎么办      他不是这种人
- What if he squeals on me? - He's not that kind of guy
我出道以来 从没相信过人
I don't trust anyone
包括你！
Including you!
我很清楚江湖规矩
I know the rules of the game
我是他的经理人 一定亲自办妥
I'll do what I promised
我不讲规矩 只讲手段
I'm not interested in rules, I want him dead
他暴露了身份 我更要他死
because he exposed his identity
现在我是老大
I'm the boss now
这个游戏我爱怎么玩就怎么玩
and you do things my way
好 我让你搞定他
Ok, you kill him for me
你搞他不定 我就搞你
If you blow it, you're dead meat
你拿了我的钱的！
After all, you got paid for it
小李 这个旧案子可能有关连
Eagle, this could be a lead
六个月前黑社会内讧 汪东源好兄弟张宏
Six months ago, Weng's partner, Lim
被人买凶暗杀了
was cut down by a professional hitman
当时 那个杀手
The killer
还枪伤了一个女歌星的眼睛
was never caught
杀手到现在还逍遥法外
but he accidentally blinded a singer
那个女歌星叫什么名字？
What was her name?
JENNIE！
Jennie!
听说眼睛到现在还看不见
She hasn't recovered yet
可惜 枪枪要人命
Life's cheap, it only takes one bullet
这不是一个普通的职业杀手
He's no ordinary assassin
希望他们是同一个人
I hope we're just looking for one man
如果我的感觉没错
If I'm not mistaken
这个不是冷血杀手
This man is not a cold-blooded murderer
枪枪要人命
It only takes one bullet
还说不是冷血？
cold blooded or not
他拼上性命都要抱着小女孩去医院抢救
He risked his life to save the little girl
如果是他枪伤了那个女歌星的话
And if he did hurt the singer by accident
他一定会跟她接触的
He must have contacted her
小庄！
Jeff?
小姐 恐怕你认错人了吧？
I'm not Jeff
对不起！我视力不大好
I'm sorry, I can't see clearly
我以为你是我的一位朋友
I thought you were my friend
这首歌非常好听
This is a beautiful song
你可不可以再唱一遍？
Could you sing it again?
我只是想唱给一个人听
I only sing for one person
小庄？
Jeff?
这首歌唱得这么有感情
Your singing is so full of emotion
听着听着我好像已经认识了你的朋友
After listening to it, I feel like I know your friend already
可惜他现在不在这儿
I wish he was here now
不论你在那儿 他都会想念你的…
Wherever he may be, you are in his thoughts
也许他根本没有离开过！
But a part of him will always be here
你连我都不信？
Don't you trust me anymore?
你问你自己！
You know why
也难怪
Of course
干我们这一行的
People in our profession
有时候连朋友也不能相信
are not supposed to trust anyone
怎么会有人知道我在哪儿上岸？
How did they know I'd go to that beach?
可能我送车去码头的时候
I might have been followed
被人跟踪
when I drove the car there
是我疏忽
That's my fault
是谁要杀我？
Who wants me dead?
问来干什么？
Why do you ask?
你该知道这个游戏是这么玩的
You know the rules
为什么当时有机会走你不走？
Why didn't you flee, after the job?
我还没有拿到钱
I haven't got my money yet
是谁要杀我？
Who wants to kill me?
如果你不暴露身份
If you hadn't exposed your identity
他根本就不会杀你
he wouldn't want you dead
我再问你 是谁要杀我？
Answer me, who wants to kill me?
你都不清楚里面还有没有子弹？
Answer me first, do you have any bullets left?
你忘了我一定会留下最后一颗子弹
I always save the last bullet
或者自杀 或者杀人！
Either for myself, or my enemy
汪海 汪东源的侄子 是他要杀你
It's Johnny Weng, Tony Weng's nephew, he wants you dead
也是他要你杀他叔叔
He hired you to kill his uncle
你真的还有一颗子弹？
Do you really have one last bullet?
小庄 谢谢你饶了我的命
Jeff, thank you for sparing me
其实我跟你一样
We are in the same boat now
都是被迫得无路可走
There's no way out for us
我们最好不要再见面了
I never want to see you again
李SIR！
Inspector Li!
李长官 蛮严重的！
Inspector Li, five dead witnesses
他在这儿
It was him
没那么巧吧？
Are you sure?
快拿他的拼图 问问这里的邻居
Show his picture to the neighbors and ask if he was here
好！
Ok
李长官 你真有灵感
Inspector Li, you hit it on the nail
我问过附近的邻居 他是住这里的
The neighbors say he lives here
你发神经呀？
Are you nuts?
JENNIE！
Jennie!
小庄 你回来啦？
Jeff, it's you?
你怎么还不来？
Why don't you come back?
我先替你拿药！
I'll be back this morning
等一下我带你去另外一个地方
We're moving to a new home
为什么？
Why?
换一个比较干净的环境
I thought you loved
对你双眼睛会好一点
to live by the sea
好呀！
do
我想搬到海边
Beautiful sea breezes
我希望能再看到海
I can imagine the view of the deep blue sea
看到天就好了！
and the clear blue sky
好 你先收拾好东西 我很快就来
Great, pack your things and wait for me
我等你！
I'll be here
为什么当时你有机会走你却不走？
You didn't leave Hong Kong when you had the chance
为什么？
What stopped you?
先生 你是不是新来倒垃圾的？
Are you the new janitor?
是的！
Yes lady
你做事怎么这么不负责任呀？
You're not doing your job properly
这里是消防通道
This is a fire-escape
把这些垃圾扔得满地都是
Look, there's garbage everywhere
万一着起火来 大家怎么逃生呀？
What happens if there's a fire?
还不快点把它搬走
I can't fly away like a phoenix
我告诉你 我们可没少交管理费
I pay my maintenance fee every month
你要是偷懒的话
If I find you lazy again
我就到管理处去告你
I'll file a complaint against you
快点搬
Don't leave...
一个也不能留下来      好…
- any garbage here - You bet lady
统统搬走 快一点
Move it all away
岂有此理
Shit
小庄 你回来啦？
Jeff, you're back
是 JENNIE！
Yes, Jennie
你有朋友来啊？
Are you with a friend?
是呀 打球的朋友
Yes, he used to play football with me
我们小时候在贫民区一块儿长大的
We grew up in the same squatter area
是呀 他叫…
Yes He's
我叫小弟呀 虾头！
I'm Dumbo, he's Mickey Mouse
原来你叫虾头呀？
You called each other that?
久别重逢真是太开心了
It's good to see you again
我可没那么开心
I don't share that feeling
老朋友见面还不开心？
You're not pleased to see your friend?
他好烦的
We're not that close
从小到大像跟屁虫一样缠着我
He's been causing me a lot of trouble
我很快不用再缠着你了
I'm here to sort it out
对呀！
Have a seat
我去给你们泡杯茶喝
Let me make you some tea
不用啦！
Don't bother
一定要的！
No need
小心啊 别烫着！
Please be careful
是呀！
Take care, Jennie
我很棒的 不会烫到自己
I know how to do it, I won't hurt myself
小庄 你去招呼小弟坐一下
Jeff, take care of Dumbo while I make the tea
进来坐吧！小弟！
Dumbo, make yourself at home
好呀 虾头！
I am, Mickey Mouse
阿婆 你每天早上盯着人家倒垃圾呀？
Ma'am, why're you so concerned about the garbage?
不是 有人给我一千块
He paid me 1,000 bucks
叫我陪你聊天
to keep you talking
先生 你别走呀！
Don't walk out on me now!
我还没有聊完呀！
I haven't had this much fun
再聊一块儿吧
in twenty years!
这场球赛你输定啦
You're going to lose this game
是吗？看到底谁会输？
Am I? Let's wait and see
你总是临门缺了那么一脚
You're always the loser
你错啦 我有最好的前锋
Not this time, I'm well prepared
可惜你的前锋是个瘸子
Let's put your preparations to the test
你一向都这么认真吗？
Are you always so determined?
是 容易的事我不做
Yes, that's my style
我也是！
Mine too!
所以我觉得我们有些相似
So we have something in common
你是说你我都不简单？不太像人吧？
Is that what you think?
像！
For sure
你们聊得好开心呀 喝杯茶！
Have some tea, whilst you catch up on old times
JENNIE 小心别弄洒了
Thanks Jennie,
对了 不要烫着！
be careful
JENNIE 帮我招呼一下小弟
Jennie, this is Dumbo's hand
喝茶！
Here's your tea
谢谢呀！         不客气
- Thank you - Pleasure
你又有朋友来了？
Is he another friend of yours?
不 是倒垃圾的阿婆
No, he's the janitor
我没垃圾可倒呀！
We don't have a janitor in this building
原来他是修水管的
Oh, he's the plumber
水管在阳台那边
There's a burst water pipe outside
小弟 我总觉得你的声音很熟
Dumbo, your voice is so familiar
我们好像在那儿听过
Have we met somewhere before?
我在酒吧见过你
I met you in the nightclub
我很喜欢你唱的歌
I loved your singing,
我请你再唱你不肯
but you didn't want to sing without Jeff there
你就是那个李先生呀？
Oh, I remember
真是太巧了
What a coincidence!
小弟 你跟JENNIE好好聊一聊
Dumbo, take care of Jennie for a while
我去一下洗手间
I'm going to the bathroom
我也去
Me too
我带你去 我房间还有一个洗手间
There's another bathroom in the bedroom
有只大老鼠
Jennie, there's a rat
又有老鼠？
Rat?
走进了厨房 我替你去捉
In the kitchen, I'll catch it
喂！是我！
Hey, don't shoot! It's me!
不要开枪
Don't shoot!
下面有人用枪对着我呐！
Somebody down there's aiming at my ass!
JENNIE！
Jennie!
究竟发生什么事？
What happened?
小庄呢？
Where's Jeff?
我知道你们俩都在骗我
I know you and Jeff lied to me
你说啊！
Tell me the truth!
你究竟是什么人？
Who the hell are you?
我是警探
I'm a cop
小庄是职业杀手
Jeff is a professional killer
他杀了人
He murdered somebody
我们一直在追捕他
I've been after him for months
我不相信
I don't believe you
JENNIE！
Jennie!
JENNIE 你听我说
Listen to me, Jennie
我不听你说
No I won't
冷静一点…
Jennie, it's true
曾爷！
Chang!
JENNIE 冷静一点！
Jennie, calm down
你听我说呀！
Listen please!
坐下！
Sit down
六个月前
Six months ago
打伤你眼睛的是他
Jeff shot your face up by accident
现在黑社会要杀他灭口
Now, his employer wants him dead
我不相信！
I don't believe it
法律是很难兼顾到人情的
I'd like to help but I can't in my position
希望你跟我们合作引他出现
I hope you'll cooperate with us
JENNIE！我是在利用你
Jennie, we're using you as bait
小庄让我抓到的话
If I can get Jeff in this time
其实这就是帮了他
I'll be able to help save his life,
总比让黑社会杀死好吧
otherwise the guy who hired him will kill him
我不管花多少钱 也要杀了他！
Name your price, I just want him dead!
他暴露身份 破坏行规
He was seen on the job
我要他死 死在我面前！
I want him wasted, the sooner the better
先存十万美金来我户口
Deposit US$100,000 into my account now
事成之后再给二十万
another US$200,000 on completion
我没看见银行收条
No money no action Mr Weng
就算现在有人用枪指着你的头
Not even if I see someone's finger on the trigger,
我也不会动手
ready to blow your head off
马上到银行调十万美金
Get the hundred grand into his account
是！汪先生！
I could have got him
你没用了 还有脸来见我？
What do you want?
你应该给他那笔钱
You should pay Jeff,
他拿不到绝不会罢休的！
or he could be a real danger to you
那又怎么样？杀我呀！
That's bullshit! I'm safe
我满街都是兄弟 叫他来呀！
Look at these guys, they're killers
出来混 总要讲个信用！
You're the boss, you should keep your word
别要来这一套
Don't talk crap
谁也改变不了我的主意
I ain't going to pay him,
你跪下来也不成
even if you beg
海哥 你就给我一个机会
Mr Weng, let me keep my word,
让我跟朋友有个交代
and pay him what I promised
我对你也会有个交代
Then I'll bring him to you
海哥 只要你高兴
Mr Weng, if it pleases you,
我就给你跪下
I will beg
滚！你真烦呀你！
Go to hell, you jerk!
要不是看你是前辈
If you hadn't worked for my father for so long
我一脚踢死你
I'd have kicked the shit out of you
他算什么？小杂碎嘛
Who is he? He doesn't deserve your sympathy
我真不明白 你为什么这么帮着他？
Why are you doing all this for Jeff?
他可是绝不简单的！
He's my best friend
不要再跟我说了
Cut the crap!
你们快下来 大哥出事啦！
Come here now! Mr Weng's been shot
给我杀了他！
Kill him!
杀了他 别让他跑！
Kill him!! Don't let him go!
大哥！
Mr Weng!
你受伤了 先回去吧！
Mr Weng, you've been hurt!
帮我杀死他！
Just kill him!
大哥 先回去吧！这里很危险
Let's go! You're in danger
去追呀！
Get after him!
你如果当我是你的朋友
If you consider me your friend,
你就一枪打死我好了
kill me now
我不想见到我的朋友
I loathe seeing you demean yourself
在别人面前跪着乞求
by begging
我是一个没用的人
Though I didn't succeed
但是我答应朋友的事 我就一定要做到
I risked my life to get your money
如果可以一枪打死你
I could have just killed you
我就不必跪着向人帮你要钱
I didn't have to beg Weng for your money
难道我就不觉得羞耻吗？
I'm not completely without honour, am I?
这个世界变啦
Our world is changing so fast
我们都不再适合这个江湖
It never used to be like this
因为我们太念旧啦！
Perhaps we are too nostalgic
或者我们幸运
Nostalgia is one of our saving graces
我不希望一辈子连一个朋友都没有
At least, when I die,
就离开这个世界
I'll know I was remembered by a friend
我最遗憾的是我欠了你一个情！
Let's settle our dues in the next life
朋友之间无所谓谁欠谁
Think we can cancel them right now,
不然要朋友来干什么？
that's what friend are for
对吗？
Right?
小庄！
A drink?
谢谢！
Thank you
JENNIE一直希望再看到天 看到海！
Jennie always wanted to live by the sea
你为她付出这么多
You've done so much for her
不知道她对你又怎么样？
I wonder how she feels about you?
喂！
Hello?
JENNIE！
Jennie!
小庄 为什么你突然走了
Jeff, why did you leave me?
留下我一个人？
You didn't say goodbye
对不起呀！我有要紧事要做
I'm sorry I had something to do
我们今天晚上就要走了
We've got to leave tonight
今晚？
Tonight?
刚才何医生通知我
Dr Ho called this afternoon
说星加坡那边有一对眼角膜
He's reserved a pair of corneas,
很多人抢着想要
but they're in Singapore
他已经帮我订下了
We have to be there by midnight,
所以最好今天晚上就要赶去
or they automatically to go someone else
好 我陪你去
Alright, I'll take you
好 我已经订了今天晚上的飞机
Ok, be at the airport at 7:30 tonight
我在机场等你啊 你一定要来
I'll meet you near Information, you must come
好 拜拜！
Of course, bye-bye
你看他会不会去？
Do you think he'll come?
去不去？
Will you go?
她没骗过我
I trust her
人都到齐了吗？走！
Everybody's here, let's go
怎样？
How's it going?
所有通道包括闸口
Right, full alert now
都不能够忽略
I want you to check,
留神点！
every inch of this place
全部布置好了
Everything's ready
他绝对跑不了
If he dares to come,
除非他不来
he will never escape
小庄！
Jeff!
你不要来 你快点走！
Get away from here, run!
神经病！
She's crazy!
小庄
Jeff!
小庄 这里好多警察 你千万不要来！
Jeff, the cops are everywhere, run away!
小庄你在那里？
Jeff, the cops want you,
他们要抓你呀 你千万不要来
don't come near me
小庄 小庄 你在这吗？
Jeff, are you there?
快点走！
Run
不要被他们抓住
Don't let them catch you
小姐 你一个人吗？
Are you alone?
小庄 快走！
Run, Jeff!
警察要抓你
The cops are after you
站住 别走
Freeze!
小庄 不要被他们抓住
Jeff, the cops are all over the place
小庄 好多警察要捉你
Jeff, the cops are everywhere!
你快点跑！快点跑！
Escape! Please get away!
小庄 快点跑！
Jeff, run!
是我 JENNIE！
It's me, Jennie!
不要动
Don't move
快走呀！
Let's go
怎么啦 长官？
What is it, officer?
难道认识女孩子也犯法吗？
Flirting is not a crime
把他跨下！
Arrest him!
大家让开呀！
Keep clear everyone!
让开 让开！
Let me through!
站住！
Don't move
停一停…
Stop!
停下！我们要检查
Stop! We have to check that luggage
对不起…
We're sorry
还不快去搜？
Open those suitcases
你在机场干什么？
What were you doing at the airport?
看女孩子！
Chasing tail!
你干那一行的？
What is your job?
替电影公司发掘明星的星探
I'm a casting agent for movie companies
为什么打警察？
Why did you run and resist arrest?
醉了！
I was drunk
站起来 走两走给我看看！
Stand up and walk a straight line
你朋友在那里？
Where is your friend?
我没有朋友
What friend?
我知道你们很够义气
I'm sure you know who I mean
我也很想有你这样的朋友
He's in grave danger
你说出来是帮了他 不是害他
Help him, tell me where he is
我只是想帮他 解决他的困难
I want to help him solve his problem
也解决我的困难
I have some questions to ask him
你自己的困难 自己解决
That's none of my business
你说的人如果是我的朋友
But if the guy you're talking about is my friend
他也是自己解决
He sure doesn't need your help
李鹰 从现在开始
From now on, you're off Weng's case
你办的案子由陈博文负责
Inspector Chan will take over
你去调查另外一件案子
I'm assigning you a new case
我想知道为什么？
I want an explanation
我对你没信心
I don't trust you
感情多于理智
Siding with the suspect,
你不会成事 只会败事
is not the way to catch him
长官 你一直都看错了我！
Sir, you don't understand how I work
对呀！我就是看错了你！所以把你换了
You said it! That's why you're off the case
我不会放弃的！
I won't give up the investigation
混账！
Bullshit!
阿曾 你跟陈博文做完它！
Chang, you're now Chan's assistant
是 长官！
Yes Sir!
你马上把姓冯的放了
Release the man you arrested at the airport
然后派人廿四小时盯着他
Give him a twenty hour surveillance
直到有新发现为止
He'll lead us to Weng's assassin
听到了没有？
Have you got that?
是 长官！
Yes Sir!
你还会不会再杀人？
Will you kill again?
当初我以为 只杀坏人不杀好人
I thought the people I killed deserved to die
其实都一样
Now, I believe everybody has the right to live
我不会再杀人
No, I won't kill again
我希望能做得到
I hope I can keep my promise
我被人跟踪
I've been followed!
警方 还有汪海的人
Weng's men, and the cops too
不过全让我甩掉了
Don't worry, I took care of them
汪海找了一批高手来对付你
Weng's hired Paul Yau to waste you
没关系 这些枪足够你应付的
Don't worry, you can use my guns and ammo
你去那儿？
Where are you going?
我替你去要回那笔钱
To get your money off Weng
晚上在教堂等我
I'll meet you in the church
你一个人去？
Are you going alone?
没问题
Yes, of course
这是我应该做的
I have to keep my promise
我总算是老江湖了
Weng is not going to hurt me,
他们总会给我点面子的
I still deserve some respect
四哥 不行就算了
Sidney, I don't need the money
我不想失去一个朋友！
I do need your friendship
曾爷…曾爷
Chang! Chang!
我…我跟踪到海天径号
I followed him to, 6 Horizon Drive
很容易找的
I almost got him
我知道
I know
本来还可以…跟踪…
Yes sir! Mr Weng!
你安心吧 我会找到他的
Don't worry, I'll find him
你安心吧 曾爷！
Chang, don't worry
小李…
Eagle
输赢并不重要 没人能赢得全世界
You can't win all the time
有时候输了不等于失败…
But you can't lose forever either
曾爷…曾爷…
Chang! Chang!
李鹰 他有没有说疑凶在那儿？
Inspector Li, did he give us anything?
你自己进去问吧！
Go ask him yourself!
小庄！
Jeff!
JENNIE 怎么啦？
Jennie, what is it?
为什么天这么暗？
Why's it so dark this morning?
不是 今天是阴天！
It's just a cloudy day
放心吧 你的眼睛会好的
Relax, it'll be alright?
我们是不是今天走？
Are we leaving today?
是！
Yes
站住！
Freeze!
是谁呀？
Who is it?
是小弟！
It's Dumbo!
他来干吗？
What does he want?
我想是来送我们的吧！
He's come to say goodbye
你还不动手？
What're you waiting for?
我是警察 不会在人家背后开枪！
I'm a cop, I don't shoot people in the back
那不是跟我们这行一样？
Another way we're the same
完全不一样！
No we're not the same!
我是执法的 你是犯法的！
I uphold the law and you break it!
我今天抓不到你
Chang died because of you
怎能跟死去的朋友交代？
I swore I'd get you this time
很对不起！
I'm sorry
我是不会让你抓到的！
But I won't let you put me in prison
你要向你的朋友交代的话
If you must take revenge for your friend
不如一枪打死我
Shoot me now
不要迫我开枪！
Don't force me to kill you
你真的开枪打我？
So you really would kill me?
我不会放过任何机会
I won't let you go this time
你不会有机会的
Ok let's see it
你不一定每次都赢
You can't win all the time
你在那儿呀？
Jeff, where are you?
小庄…
Jeff!
小弟呢？小弟在那儿？
Where's Dumbo? Where is he?
在你面前
Right in front of you
你不要抓他
Don't take him away
JENNIE！
Jennie!
小庄答应过我不会再杀人的了
Jeff's promised me he'll never kill again
你先把枪放下
Put that gun down
JENNIE 把枪放下
Jennie, put that gun down
我不放下 除非他让我们走
Not unless he leaves us alone
我求求你 让我们走吧！
I beg you, please, let us go
JENNIE！      我不会让你抓他
- Jennie! - I'll never let you arrest him
我有没有打中他？他有没有死？
Did I kill him? Is he dead?
我不是真的想开枪打他 我不是真心的…
I didn't mean to kill him, I didn't mean it
他没事！
He's alright
我不是真的
I didn't mean to
他没有死！
He's alright
镇静点 别害怕
Calm down, be brave
别出去
You stay there!
小庄…小庄…
Jeff...Jeff
就算你要抓我 也先要一起杀出去
Let's get out of here, then you can arrest me
先把JENNIE救走再说
Let's get Jennie out of here
我的车在外面！
The car's outside
走！
Come on!
我不会让你抓到警察局的
I won't let you put me behind bars
把枪扔掉！
Throw the gun down
我知道你不会杀警察的
I know you won't kill a cop
谢谢！
Thank you
我知道你根本可以一枪打死我
You could have killed me with one shot
在我没有了解敌人之前
I don't kill anybody
我是不会随便杀掉他的
until I know they are the real enemy
你了解我吗？
Do you really know me?
有时候 命运可真会弄人
Sometimes fate controls everything
想不到了解我的 竟然是一个警察
The only person who really knows me turns out to be a cop
其实你是可以放弃的
But you could always give up
我也想过 只是我承诺过要做的事
No, I've made a promise,
一定要做到
I keep my word
我还真有点羡慕你
Sometimes, I really envy your freedom
有时我想做的事 却做不到
I just don't have it
我相信正义
I believe in justice
可是没人相信我
but nobody trusts me
好人通常被人误解！
I have the same problem
你一点都不像是个警察
You're an unusual cop
你也不像个杀手
And you're an unusual killer too
很抱歉 连累了你
I'm sorry to drag you into this mess
我只想知道谁是幕后主持？
Tell me, who is behind all this?
行有行规 这个我就帮不了你
That's not my game, I play by the rules
我知道你不会说的
I knew you'd never tell me
不过你要走的路很长
Take care of Jennie
要格外小心
Weng won't stop untill he kills you
我还是要抓你的
You'd better let me arrest you
我们暂时住一晚
We'll stay here tonight
等我朋友把钱拿来之后
Then Sidney will bring me my money,
明天我们就可以飞去美国
and we'll leave tomorrow
不知道那些人会不会找到这儿来？
I'm scared those gangsters will find us here
不会的！
Don't worry
这里不会有人来的 你放心
This is an out of the way place
怎么一点光都没有？
Why is it so dark?
我什么都看不见？
I can hardly see anything
小庄 小庄…快点开灯？
Jeff, turn on the lights, please
怎么还不开灯？
Why don't you turn on the lights?
小庄！
Jeff!
小庄 开灯呀！
Jeff, turn on the lights!
我看这里可能是暂时停电
There has been a power cut
你的朋友到底会不会来？
Will your friend come back with the money?
会的 他一定会来
I'm sure he will
大哥
Boss
交给保罗的十万元美金准备好啦
Here's the US$100,000. Please check it
就是不知道他能不能搞定小庄呢？
Do you think Paul Yau will be able to kill Jeff?
大哥 冯刚来了！
Boss, Sidney Fung's here
如果他再出卖你 你怎么样？
If he betrays you again, then what?
我仍然当他是我的朋友
I'd still treat him as my friend
他到底帮过我
He was so good to me
小庄那笔钱呢？
Where is Jeff's money?
他在那里？
Where the hell is he?
真正够朋友的没有几个
I wish I could have a friend like you
有的 只是太少
You will, one of these days
把枪放下 把枪放下
Drop your guns!
你的手不是废的吗？
Your right hand still works?
是有点废
Yes, well enough
不过还有点职业水准
It still fires a gun, fast and accurate
你们这一行是死路一条
You've got no way out,
为什么还要走下去？
why're you doing all this?
那么你教我怎么走才对？
You tell me, what's the alternative?
那笔钱呢？
Where's the money?
阿成！
Give it!
你太不够运气了
I'm one step ahead
为什么你不杀我的头？
Why didn't you shoot me in the head?
对！
Right
没拿枪那么久！水准是差了点
Maybe I'm just not a professional anymore
如果有机会我真想重新来过
I wish I could start all over again
可惜…
It's a pity
我要拿那笔钱
Give me the cash
小庄在那里？
Where is Jeff?
先把钱给他
Give me the money first
这就叫道义…
We owe it to him
废话！
Hypocrite!
你们这一行 究竟还讲不讲道义？
Do all killers have a sense of honor?
这世界变了 没什么人会讲的了！
Our world is changing so fast, honor's
阿叔 做人做得这么辛苦
Sidney, sometimes I think you're not human
不如做狗算了
You're more like a dog
其实我们两个人一样
At least we have one thing in common
都是靠枪吃饭的
We both use guns for our living
不过 用枪的方法不同而已
Just our motivation's different
对吗？
Right?
做狗也要整齐一点！
In some ways dogs are superior to men
你再不说小庄在那儿
If you don't tell me where Jeff is
你想做狗也难
This is your funeral
把这个废物掉这垃圾池
Throw this garbage away
拿钱来！
Give me the money
你还有子弹吗？
Are you sure you still got bullets?
试试看
You want a bet?
干我们这行的 一定留下最后一颗子弹
Jeff said, always save one last slug
或者杀人 或者自杀
Either for yourself, or your enemy
快点！
Quick!
转过身
Turn around!
计算错误 真失败
Godamnit!
快点追！
Get him!
我想你帮我做件事
I want you to promise me one thing
万一我被打死 眼睛没受到伤害
if I don't make it
马上把我送到医院
Take me to a hospital
把我的眼角膜 移植给JENNIE
Get the doctors to operate, my corneas are for Jennie
如果办不到 一定要把钱交给她
If you can't do that, organize my money
送她上飞机
and send her abroad for surgery
就没别的选择？
Don't think like that
我一生人唯一做得对的 就是这一次
It's the first decent thing I've ever done
你能不帮？
Will you help me?
怎么啦？
What's that noise?
是不是有人来？
Who is it Jeff?
没事 来！
It's Sidney Fung
四哥
Sidney
你的钱 我已经替你拿回来了！
Here's your money I fought for it like a man
对朋友 总算有个交代
This is my last tribute to a friend
四哥 你辛苦啦
Sidney, you didn't have to do this
他说我是狗
He said I was a dog
我也不知道 我究竟是人
Now I'm not sure if I'm human,
还是狗？
or a dog?
四哥 没有人有资格这样说你
Sidney, nobody can call you a dog
四哥 四哥！
Sidney, Sidney!
四哥！
Sidney!
四哥 四哥 你醒醒
Sidney, Sidney, are you alright?
我是不是狗？
Am I a dog?
不是 你不是狗 你是人！
No, you're not a dog. You're a great man!
我跟你都不再适合这个江湖了
We're outmoded characters, outcasts of our community
我不愿意像狗一样被人打死
I don't want to die like a dog
可惜 我连最后一颗子弹都没有
But you see, I didn't keep one last bullet
我有…！
I have one
小庄！
Jeff!
你坐在这里不要动
Jennie, stay where you are
不要离开我！
Don't leave me alone!
你想怎么样？
What are you going to do?
我要杀出去！
Storm my way out!
你不要再杀人行不行？
Don't kill anymore, please?
把枪放下跟我走！
Give up your guns and come with me
把枪放下？十几年的朋友
What? You say me kill Sidney
我就这么一枪把他打死了！
He was my best friend
你现在叫我把枪放下
And you dare to tell me to give up?
我朋友死的时候
When Chang died
我也想过一枪把你打死
I swore I'd kill you
但是我现在不想看到你死
But now I don't want you to get killed
你带着JENNIE快点走吧！
Get out of here with Jennie
走？
How?
天涯海角他们也会追杀我
They'll chase me to the ends of the earth
没路走 我就要跟他们拼
I have nowhere to go
你现在出去告诉他们你是警察
Get out there and tell them you're cop,
看他们会不会把枪放下？
see if they give up their guns
JENNIE！      小庄！
- Jennie! - Jeff!
小庄呀…
Jeff!
小弟！
Dumbo!
谢啦 虾头！
Thanks, Mickey Mouse!
小弟 我欠你的！
Dumbo, I owe you
别说谁欠谁
You don't owe me nothing
人情债永远还不完的
This is the gift of friendship
祝你好运！
Good luck!
JENNIE 不要跑！
Jennie, take cover!
别动呀！
Don't move!
JENNIE！
Jennie!
小弟…
Dumbo!
拿枪来！
Give me gun!
虾头 接着！
Mickey Mouse, here!
你的枪法准不准？
How good a shot are you?
不准怎么能当警察？
I'm a cop, I've got to be good!
做了朋友这么久
We've been through so much together,
我还不知道你的真名字！
I don't even know your name
有需要知道吗？
Is it important?
我怕这件事完了之后
Whether we win or lose,
你就算不死也会远走
you ain't going to be around
让我记得曾经 有过这么一个朋友也好
I'd like to have a name to remember you by forever
那么你想我死 还是想我走？
Would you rather see me dead or set free?
如果不是注定的话 我两样都不想
If fate spares us, I don't want either
总算你够朋友
You're a helluva good friend!
你不是给我起了个名字叫虾头吗？
Remember me as Mickey Mouse, why not?
不要过去呀！
Come back!
我要找我的朋友
I must find my friend
不要伤害她 你不要伤害她！
Leave her alone, she's innocent!
走！
Move!
把枪放下！
Drop your gun!
把枪放下
Drop your gun
你放不放？你妈的
Godamnit! You heard me? Hurry up!
小庄 小庄 你在那儿呀？
Jeff, where are you, Jeff?
JENNIE 你不要怕 我就在你前面
Jennie, don't be afraid, I'm in front of you
把枪放下
Drop your gun
JENNIE 你不要乱动呀
Jennie, don't move an inch
你不要伤害她
Don't hurt her
我不会伤害她
No, I won't hurt her
我会杀死她
I'll just kill her
你放了她
Release her!
别乱来
Stop
你先把她放了
Let her go
不放！
No way!
不放又怎么样？
What if I don't?
把枪放下
Drop your guns!
小弟！
Dumbo!
你答应过我的事 一定要做到
Will you do what you've promised?
没问题！
No problem
你不要忘了 你背后还有个朋友支持你
Don't forget, there's always a friend to back you up!
你们放不放？不放我就打死她
Drop the guns, or I'll kill her
你他妈的还不放下？
Drop your guns, idiots!
虾头…
Mickey Mouse
虾头！
小庄！
Jeff!
JENNIE！
Jennie!
小庄！小庄 你在那里？
Jeff, where are you?
小庄！
Jeff!
不许动！
Don't move!
我不动！我投降…
Ok! Ok! I surrender,
我愿意跟警方合作 快铐我呀！
I'll cooperate, arrest me please!
你一点都不像是个警察
You're an unusual cop
你也不像个杀手
And you're an unusual killer too
我相信正义
I believe in justice
可是没人相信我
but nobody trusts me
好人通常被人误解！
I have the same problem
把他跨下
Arrest him
让我来！
I'll do it!
铐我呀 铐我回去
Arrest me, arrest me
我要求警方保护我 你们快铐我呀！
Arrest me! I'm asking for police custody!
我合作 快铐我！
I'm a criminal, arrest me!
虾头…
Mickey Mouse...